<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on goshSAMit</title>
    <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on goshSAMit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://goshsamit.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Traefik and PiHole</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/traefik-and-pihole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/traefik-and-pihole/</guid>
      <description>Project I was getting tired of entering IP addresses and having to click through the &amp;ldquo;connection not secure&amp;rdquo; messaging to get into my homelab services. I found a video by TechnoTim on YouTube where he walks through the &amp;ldquo;how-to&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; of setting up Traefik as a cert manager and local DNS records on PiHole. So instead of copying his tutorial, I will just link it here.
 TechnoTim&amp;rsquo;s website with tutorial TechnoTim&amp;rsquo;s Youtube tutorial  Domain Name System Part of this project focuses on creating local Domain Name System (DNS) records, which allow you to access services in a browser using domain names instead of IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/homepage-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/homepage-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>Intro Homepage is a simple dashboard allowing users to set up a single page to get a quick view of services running on their network, resource utilization, and important links. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good project to start working with docker containers, as you can create a docker container to run your homepage instance, which is what this guide will show.
 If you would like to see the configuration files for my own homepage dashboard, please follow this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Network</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-network/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is a walk-through guide of how I set up home network and how to set up VLANs on a TP-Link Managed Switch.
My network at home is set into 3 Virtual Local Area Networks (VLAN). The first is VLAN 1, and it is the default network that my family&amp;rsquo;s everyday devices connect to. The second is VLAN 20. It is for smart devices that have questionable security vulnerabilities. I buy devices that I generally trust, but you can&amp;rsquo;t be too careful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Lab Hardware</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-lab-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-lab-hardware/</guid>
      <description>My home lab came about from asking the question &amp;ldquo;how am I supposed to get an IT job that requires experience, without experience?&amp;rdquo; On top of new responsibilities at my current role, my home lab is a great place to practice, learn, try new things, and fail, all without worry about taking down production.
I figure my hardware is a good place to start. I&amp;rsquo;ll make a list of all the hardware and what I am doing with it or what I plan to do with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Attached Storage</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/network-attached-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/network-attached-storage/</guid>
      <description>What is Network Attached Storage? Networked attached storage, or NAS, is a storage device that can be access through a network, rather than being directly connected to a device. Basically, it&amp;rsquo;s a portable hard-drive that anyone on the network can access (but is not actually portable). Users directly accessing the network as well as users outside the network but using a VPN to remotely connect to the network can access a NAS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
