<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>goshSAMit</title>
    <link>https://goshsamit.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on goshSAMit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://goshsamit.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VLAN Basics</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/topics/virtual-local-area-network-vlan-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/topics/virtual-local-area-network-vlan-basics/</guid>
      <description>Virtual Local Area Network (VLAN) Basics In my home, I was looking for a way to keep my personal devices separate from any smart devices, as those devices can be less secure. One way I could handle this is to set up two Local Area Networks (LAN), one for my personal devices and one for the smart devices. Each would have their own switch and connection to the router and neither would be able to talk to the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Commands</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/topics/git-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/topics/git-commands/</guid>
      <description>Steps to connect to a git repo  Create the repo on Github Create a folder on your local device that you want to old the repo git clone {repo_url_from_github} git remote set-url origin {repo_url_from_github} git config &amp;ndash;global user.name “name&amp;quot; git config &amp;ndash;global user.email “email” git branch newbranch git checkout newbranch make changes to code git add . git commit . -m &amp;ldquo;commit message&amp;rdquo; git push origin main Go to github and create a new pull request  Steps to start a repo on local and push to github  In Progress  Various git commands  git pull origin main ==&amp;gt; pulls from the main branch to local checked out branch git remote add {alias} {url} -&amp;gt; git remote add origin github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/homepage-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/homepage-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>Intro Homepage is a simple dashboard allowing users to set up a single page to get a quick view of services running on their network, resource utilization, and important links. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good project to start working with docker containers, as you can create a docker container to run your homepage instance, which is what this guide will show.
 If you would like to see the configuration files for my own homepage dashboard, please follow this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install Docker and Docker Compose on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/topics/how-to-install-docker-and-docker-compose-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/topics/how-to-install-docker-and-docker-compose-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>run the following commands to set up docker&amp;rsquo;s apt repository  # Add Docker&#39;s official GPG key: sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install ca-certificates curl sudo install -m 0755 -d /etc/apt/keyrings sudo curl -fsSL https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu/gpg -o /etc/apt/keyrings/docker.asc sudo chmod a+r /etc/apt/keyrings/docker.asc # Add the repository to Apt sources: echo \ &amp;quot;deb [arch=$(dpkg --print-architecture) signed-by=/etc/apt/keyrings/docker.asc] https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu \ $(. /etc/os-release &amp;amp;&amp;amp; echo &amp;quot;${UBUNTU_CODENAME:-$VERSION_CODENAME}&amp;quot;) stable&amp;quot; | \ sudo tee /etc/apt/sources.list.d/docker.list &amp;gt; /dev/null sudo apt-get update run the following command to install the latest version of docker  sudo apt-get install docker-ce docker-ce-cli containerd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Network</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-network/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is a walk-through guide of how I set up home network and how to set up VLANs on a TP-Link Managed Switch.
My network at home is set into 3 Virtual Local Area Networks (VLAN). The first is VLAN 1, and it is the default network that my family&amp;rsquo;s everyday devices connect to. The second is VLAN 20. It is for smart devices that have questionable security vulnerabilities. I buy devices that I generally trust, but you can&amp;rsquo;t be too careful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 20:57:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Download Resume (To Be Added)  Past I was a Quality Assurance Consultant responsible for the manual and automated test of web apps, mobile apps, and POS apps. I consulted for Huntington Bank, BMW Financial Services, and Bath &amp;amp; Body Works. I graduated from Ohio University with a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Information and Telecommunication Systems.
Present I am currently a Senior Quality Engineer in Restaurant Technology at Wendy&amp;rsquo;s. I am responsible for quality of software and hardware, test lab maintenance, and test automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Lab Hardware</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-lab-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-lab-hardware/</guid>
      <description>My home lab came about from asking the question &amp;ldquo;how am I supposed to get an IT job that requires experience, without experience?&amp;rdquo; On top of new responsibilities at my current role, my home lab is a great place to practice, learn, try new things, and fail, all without worry about taking down production.
I figure my hardware is a good place to start. I&amp;rsquo;ll make a list of all the hardware and what I am doing with it or what I plan to do with it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
