<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>homelab on goshSAMit</title>
    <link>https://goshsamit.com/tags/homelab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in homelab on goshSAMit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://goshsamit.com/tags/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Homepage Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/homepage-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/homepage-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>Intro Homepage is a simple dashboard allowing users to set up a single page to get a quick view of services running on their network, resource utilization, and important links. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good project to start working with docker containers, as you can create a docker container to run your homepage instance, which is what this guide will show.
Steps  Install docker and docker compose with this guide On your docker machine (mine is a VM running Ubuntu server), create a folder where you want to keep your homepage files  mkdir homepage &amp;ldquo;CD&amp;rdquo; into that directory  cd homepage Create two new files inside that directory called &amp;ldquo;docker-compose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Network</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-network/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is a walk-through guide of how I set up home network and how to set up VLANs on a TP-Link Managed Switch.
My network at home is set into 3 Virtual Local Area Networks (VLAN). The first is VLAN 1, and it is the default network that my family&amp;rsquo;s everyday devices connect to. The second is VLAN 20. It is for smart devices that have questionable security vulnerabilities. I buy devices that I generally trust, but you can&amp;rsquo;t be too careful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Lab Hardware</title>
      <link>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-lab-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://goshsamit.com/projects/home-lab-hardware/</guid>
      <description>My home lab came about from asking the question &amp;ldquo;how am I supposed to get an IT job that requires experience, without experience?&amp;rdquo; On top of new responsibilities at my current role, my home lab is a great place to practice, learn, try new things, and fail, all without worry about taking down production.
I figure my hardware is a good place to start. I&amp;rsquo;ll make a list of all the hardware and what I am doing with it or what I plan to do with it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
